hello my name is Andrew Sweeney welcome
to my podcast today I'm going to read
you some of my recent writing some
rather imagistic prose poems which
express some ideas that I've been
wanting to put into a language that is
not prosaic in other words that cuts
beneath the level of rationality and
touches us on some visceral level so
this one's called the double face and it
makes a reference to Allen Ginsberg and
his famous poem howl I've seen the best
minds of this generation turned into
lovey ciphers vacuums and holes of
ideology walking lockstep into a prison
of text made perfectly redundant able to
repeat truisms memes like viperous
phantoms in the death rattle of the
social network and yet I've also seen a
mother in the park and a child with an 8
horn and I know that there are still
snails and that there are still clouds
and mythologies and Mother's Milk
and invisible allies made of rain and
the lovemaking of foxes I've seen the
best minds of this generation smashed
against ones and zeros of cellular
collapse of jargon and obscure
parentheses become biological machines
circle the poisonous rain hypnotized by
the dark illumination glued to the
pavement like drooling vipers frenzied
and pumped up with mechanical music and
a nothingness not yet hitherto imagined
and yet I've seen a young boy embrace a
young girl next to a highway the light
in his eyes filled with early dawn is
hard awake with affections and
intimations of a new freedom and the
divine soul suddenly becoming a
possibility
I've seen the lousy little poets trying
to sound like Charlie Manson reference
to Leonard Cohen song and yet I heard
your language of seas and shells and
torn fabric
I saw your heroic breasts full of pride
and beauty I saw you kiss the crowd
I saw you caressed me with eyes and I
was witness to your divine spark can we
stop the world from dying
no it dies a greater death every moment
and an even greater death and an even
greater birth for here we stand in the
jaws of annihilation as Moloch children
of the New World Order were all the
metaphysical farms collapse no I won't
get on that train that leads straight to
the ovens and prays the digital moon or
the chemical Sun for I know that there
is still Helius the god of suns and
there is still cynthia the goddess of
the moon and that even if we have
forgotten what a human being is and
there is nowhere to live can I not say I
was grateful indeed blessed for just one
afternoon with you sipping tea and
falling into love's reason while the
gentle hum of engines did not disturb
the primeval silence no I can't be
hypnotized by nullity there is still
juice in here there is still a place
where the angel comes there are still
the forest of foxes and cranes and all
kinds of hallelujah the broken and the
holy the full the crack the perfect
appearance the tiny insect of exquisite
beauty do I speak too directly or would
you like to put a gas mask on my face do
you have an iron lung for my words am I
saying things that cannot be said here
in the land of shadows
well I am saying them anyway because I
am the lover and the lover risks all and
that is how it is and how it evermore
shall be amen yes I've seen the future
and that kind of horror cannot be held
in the human heart for long for soon we
will be dancing soon we will be
forgetting soon the massive drift of
continent
the heavenly music soon the donkeys will
ride again in the electric dawn the
sheep grow wings and souls the death
rattle will stop and there will be just
the man and the woman again
alone in the Garden of Eden with the
fruit and the Serpent's joke and the
world tree all still in place for it is
always eating deer even as I gaze into
the visage of the Beast love still moves
on the deep even here in this place that
is not even a place where there is
nowhere to live no where to be
not even the semblance of a home I don't
blame you for sleeping outside broken
poet because our homes are no longer
homes our hearts no longer hearts they
have been eating my mouths and they have
been stunned by demons and they are
nearly irredeemable except that kiss
waiting on the banister that kiss that
never left that never was that came and
yet that kiss the redeems even one so
foolish as I so that was called the
double face and the next one is called
the hipsters lament the clever idiots
are on the banister they glare at you
with their savant eyes but they never
really touch you the word Smiths are
deep in their furnace working their set
of huge their been in a revolution but
they never really know what they say oh
how they burn in their cool intellect
how they drift away from their bodies
like angry sleepers they think they can
win you through mere words and sometimes
they succeed for a while until the next
clever idiot comes along to dress you in
a new lexicon no you are just another
naked man under the hammer when the
floods came when the harsh times arrived
your tenured halls could not immunize
you to rats and plagues
you thought you were particularly clever
mr. Jones but you never really learned
to laugh with all the metaphors you
threw it people know you never really
heard the ancient language though you
mastered the revolutionary lingo
you never shuddered in the embrace of
the deep how pride caused you to show
all your feathers but how'd they became
in the bright light have you ran to the
skirts of mother banished from your
kingdom
another hipster under the wheel raging
against the father in the sky with
nothing in your womb the next one I call
the soft GU leg and it's similarly a
critique of a certain kind of hollow
revolutionary jingoism it's much it's
much influenced from reading Alexander
Solzhenitsyn and his it's his
experiences in the gulanite but it also
points towards another kind of
emancipation but I would say it's a more
spiritual than anything else the soft GU
leg
comrade Xu have been a prisoner of the
mines jargon of ideological position a
prisoner of winning a prisoner of losing
a prisoner of niall ism a prisoner of
the eternal reward
comrade X of the future techno you Tokyo
and bloody chains of history of lockjaw
social norms and celebrity wet dreams of
Karl Marx and Ayn Rand a sexual monsters
and peered and hangs of the right and of
the left and of the rainbow and of the
dark cloud of hope and despair and all
those things are your chains now comrade
X free yourself from that soft goo leg
become your own precious soul confess
repent
comrade X free yourself even from your
own liberation from the mechanical beat
from the robotic gyrations from the
academic
patience comrade X every man and woman
is a stranger on this boat in a dark sea
and yet edan still haunts the galleys
comrade X do not divide the world into
the righteous and holy but know that the
devil and the angel live in your own
heart
comrade X can you survive the
interrogation of your own mind the depth
of the mirror
comrade X free yourself from the hard
flesh and the soft line from
emancipatory ejaculation comrade X free
yourself even from losing your own
chains and then put them on for me
tonight
like a lap dancer of the gods comrade X
drive your stake into the very earth
become responsible and awake to a child
to a flower to a corpse to laughter to
the fight comrade X know that the
revolution is a giggle and a sham and
that the adversary stalks your own heart
and that your soul is a woman who has
been locked in a dark hole comrade X it
is the hearts expression that gives
birth to the world wrestling with dark
hallucinations a drop of poison from the
monster spleen comrade X now lower
yourself to the earth and begin lifting
up others for that is enough for that is
what is needed to wake the shuffling
dead to give meaning to tragedy and
smiles to children
comrade X what will you do after the
rape of the world and is your freedom
earned through the depth of your gesture
that the sharpness of your thought
through the tenderness of your mercy
comrade X comrade X the dream is over
comrade X the blood flows under the
streets
comrade X are you a man or a machine a
soul or a cipher a collective or a
person a song or a megaphone
radix I hear the gravel in your throat
comrade X I can hear you singing for the
executioner this is a nameless poem I
had declared the world an illusion or a
joke until you walk naked into the room
I had lit out four fireplaces until you
brought me back to your smoldering
Mountain I wore dark robes fed entrails
to scorpions until you brought me some
milk and honey I wanted to be a corpse
until you put mercury in my blood this
morning was only grey dung until you
crowned me with a kiss on the nape there
are so many ways there are so many days
like this you undo my plans my arc of
logic falls like a card house on your
lap the old pure to none and me shrieked
when you showed me your thigh I tried to
write about the coming apocalypse but
you were still giggling I tried
renunciation and smashing mirrors but
that didn't work either my over earnest
prose left you laughing in a midnight
full of wolves and now I am building a
little Ark to try to escape from you but
it is no use the waters have already
drowned that boat Here I am naked on the
operating table I am paralyzed nearly
lifeless and yet I feel your hands all
over me planting spring flowers in my
crania I don't know the difference
anymore between orgasm and epilepsy
between religion and pornography the
more lines are drawn the more chains the
more space opens up everything is
paradox here somewhere near your
vertebrae
did I forget what to say again oh love
there is nothing wrong with my cock
there is nothing wrong with your pussy
they want to be included just like
little children they chased each other
around the table while the mine does
complex crossword puzzles
they are like horses and saddles like
Stalingrad in white knights there is no
reason for them and yet isn't the beauty
of a snail the reason let us not politic
a minute
and sound the trumpets of love after all
nobody is listening to our love cries
but the Archangel and maybe the
neighbors anything to break the lock jaw
evening is fine let us be true
renunciants give up our heavy conceptual
clothing let's be mad goats geriatric
rock stars instead of cows and sheep do
you think that God wanted an iron lock
for a vagina do you think that God
wanted pale monuments to be erected in
eternal winter spring is here you
pitiful fools you must dance with pan
with Lucifer with Cynthia who cares
the moon is in cancer who cares that the
Sun is bleeding after all this is peri
and everybody is kissing wildly doesn't
the snot Green River and bumptious Notre
Dame still cry out oh god oh god the
beauty the beauty an earlobe a pencil a
star so let us be chaste and find love
again where love was wanting like some
bright virgin with her ukulele and
pigtails
let us sing the song of love after all
love is not gone anywhere she is still
here with her knee socks her books of
poetry her ridiculous existential
questions she is still here whispering
in our ear love love as woken